now let's try to figure out Tomasulo
timing on our own suppose we have a
processor with these latencies a load
takes one cycle to execute an ad the x1
cycle and a multiply takes five cycle
suppose that the latencies of
instruction execution are load one cycle
add one cycle and multiply five cycles
suppose we also have this number of
reservation stations we have one load
reservation station to add and to
multiply reservation stations and
finally we need to know what's allowed
in the same cycle and for that issuing
and then this patching instruction in
the same cycle is not allowed capturing
the upper end and then dispatch in an
instruction in the same cycle is not
allowed in this processor and finally if
a reservation station is freed it cannot
be used in the same cycle again for
another instruction so once we free a
reservation station it only becomes
eligible for issuing another instruction
in the next cycle these are the
instructions we have and what we need to
now do is figure out the timing for them
when do they issue dispatch and write to
get you started these four instructions
will issue in cycles 1 2 3 & 4 this quiz
has two parts part one is for you to
figure out for these four instructions
that issue in cycles 1 2 3 & 4
when do they dispatch for each one of
them and when does each one of them
write its result